Alejandro Jose Torres Valero

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER
Gmail | GitHub | Linkedin | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with over +5000 hours of coding experience. Worked with small teams while developing projects based on React, CSS, and Ruby on Rails. An enthusiast for creating clean code and accessible design. Capable of learning new languages, frameworks, and tools quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full-stack Web Developer

Remote May 2022 – Present

<u>Pokedex</u> — Developed a search option where users can search for different types of pokemon in a list and can see a brief description of it. At the same time, it will change the background of the pokemon depending on the type.

• Built with JavaScript | HTML | CSS | webpack | API's

<u>Math-magicians</u> — Created a web app that shows a calculator, which can do basic mathematical operations. Designed two more different routes where the user can change, to see different kinds of quotes and a home page.

Built with: React | JavaScript | CSS | HTML | API's

<u>Bike Rentals</u> – Developed a webapp where the user can log in/sign up on the page. After successfully logging in to the page they can now see a list of bikes they can rent adding the start date, end date, location, and a specific motorcycle, this can be done by clicking the bike itself or by going to the reservations page itself where they can choose them by names.

• Built with: Ruby | Ruby on Rails | Rspec | React | JavaScript | CSS | APIs | Gems

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

June 2022 – August 2022

- Mentored 2 junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to 2 web junior developers.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE May 2022 - Present

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Connected and managed a group of several people from different parts of the world while developing projects on short deadlines.